RYAN TAYLOR

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER

ryan@ryantaylor.info (801) 448-6584

Profile

I am a software developer with more than 10 years of experience working with web technologies. I am interested in complex web systems built using Java, Javascript, Python and the great tools and frameworks that surround those technologies. I enjoy learning about the latest trends in software, and rediscovering classic books about best practices and design patterns.

Skills Knowledge and Abilities

Design Oriented
I value well-designed
software that emphasizes
security, reliability,
readability, and testability.

Web Focused

I have a deep
understanding of the web
technology stack,
including: Nginx, Apache,
HTTP(S), and SQL.

Experienced
I have developed and maintained large-scale applications based in Java, Javascript, Python and PHP.

Technical Skills

Javascript	Java	PHP
Python	Ruby	HTML & CSS
Git	Docker	Linux

Professional Experience

Software Engineer/Architect

University of Utah

2010-Present

Built and maintained various web applications. I managed team projects to build new web apps and add features to legacy applications. These projects include: an application for hiring TAs, an application for helping students apply for scholarships, a scheduling system for reserving lab tools, and several more.

Website Maintenance and Development

Ticket Exchange Utah

2006-2010

Maintained website. Built web applications for internal inventory tracking. Automated business processes to reduce the amount of manual work required.

Software Developer

Verite 2004-2006

Built custom websites for clients using PHP, HTML, Javascript, CSS and C#. Handled bug fixes and feature requests for legacy software.

Education

B.S. in Computer Science

University of Utah

2009